After spending two days
in Kinosaki Onsen,
we head towards Kyoto
to spend the next five days
exploring the city,
along with a day trip to Nara.
All right, we just arrived in Kyoto
and yeah, arrived quite late.
So now we're just out on the prowl
to get some dinner
and I know just the right place
for us tonight.
So let's head in.
We are very close to the
top of Mount Inari
and honestly, not as bad as I thought.
I thought it would be a bit tougher,
but once you get up to the
crossroad area,
people start to thin out and
you get a lot of photo
and video opportunities if that's
what you're looking for.
Definitely recommend taking the walk up.
It's really not that bad.
Just take your time and you should
be just all right.
All right, I'm making my way
down Mount Inari
and towards Kyoto and a little bit later
our restaurant reservation.
Look at this, an Aquarius is ¥250.
That is the mountain tax in effect.
Usually like ¥150 or something like that.
Yep, mountain tax.
If you can make it, make
it down the mountain
and avoid the mountain tax.
Look at this guys.
Look at this, look at this.
The lower you get, the lower
the price also becomes.
The mountain tax is less.
This is the Pocari Sweat.
After finishing up at Fushimi Inari,
we head to our dinner reservation
at Mouriya Gion,
a teppanyaki restaurant
specialized in Kobe beef.
The menu consisted of
a couple of starters,
including flounder fish.
This is flounder fish and so this
is Japan's green pepper "sansho"
butter, white wine
and white vinegar.
But the main event is
the A5 Kobe beef.
The preparation was meticulous
and it was interesting
to watch the chef
prepare the beef right in front of us.
We end the dinner with a simple dessert
and some hot tea.
The following morning
we head to Arashiyama
to explore some of its quieter corners.
As lunch time rolls around,
we stop by a place
called Itsuki Chaya,
a restaurant known for its
beautifully prepared set meals
that highlight seasonal ingredients.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry too.
We also made sure to make
room for a little visit to Kumonocha,
a small dessert shop known for
its cloud shaped cakes.
After spending the morning visiting temples,
we head back to downtown Kyoto
and stop by Nishiki Market.
Is it good?
It's fat.
where do we go,
where do we go.
Give him a chance to clean up for you
So good.
Very, very chewy.
I do not recommend this.
The next morning, we visited
a beautiful tea house
known for their clear Hanawarabi,
a type of clear mochi with edible flowers.
After the tea house, we head down
to the Higashiyama area
and explore the city's old historic district.
All right, we are at the Nijo Castle.
And as you can see, it's very dark,
except for some light illuminations
around the castle because we're at,
I believe it's called
the Naked Sakura Festival.
Essentially, they're lighting up Nijo Castle
with some light illuminations,
kind of like team Labs I guess,
is the closest thing I would
compare it to, but yeah.
Yeah, and we also rented these lanterns.
Alright, we are on a day trip to...
And first stop is a pretty
famous mochi place.
You've probably seen it all
over social media.
Classic red bean.
It's good.
It's a little bit cold.
I wish it was a little bit warmer.
It's still alright, you know.
But lots of people right now.
So maybe we'll circle back later.
Just waiting for Lisa to get up here.
Here she comes.
Taking her time.
All good.
Are you hungry?
Hungry, hungry, hungry...
On our final evening in the city,
we make our way to the old district,
wandering its lantern-lit streets.
We came across a special evening event
at Kiyomizu-dera
that only occurs three times a year.